339 Eastern Avenue SE, Grand Rapids, MI 49503

☐ +1 (248) 514-7944 | wanovak@gmail.com | ☐ wanovak | 🖹 wanovak | 🛅 wanovak

## **Summary**

Current Senior Software Engineer at start-up company Conga, and Agile Team Lead for workforce accelerator Trilogy Education Services. 7+ years experience specializing in full-stack development, infrastructure planning and automation, integration, and performance analysis. A breadth of experience in software engineering, digital electronics engineering, and program management. Passionate about software since entering the world of HTML/CSS at age 11, and always excited to take on new tasks and challenges outside the comfort zone.

## Work Experience \_

### **Trilogy Education Services**

New York, NY

AGILE TEAM LEAD Sept. 2019 - Present

- Coached students through 8-week industry-like Agile project to develop team skills and technical proficiency.
- · Aided students in technical scoping, programming, and quality assurance tasks.
- Prepared lesson plans and demonstrations to fill gaps in course materials.

Conga (formerly Octiv) Broomfield, CO

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2016 - Present

- · Co-led greenfield effort to design, build, and deploy at scale microservices-based product offering consisting of polyglot stack and IaC tooling.
- · Introduced dynamic analysis practices and customer-facing plan to address application performance issues, directly leading to the retention of two \$1MM+ ARR client accounts. Achieved 70% performance gain from implementation of analysis findings.
- · Developed auto-generating UML-based sequence diagramming system to document complex microservices interactions.
- · Participated as a senior member of an Agile, product-driven engineering team to consistently deliver robust features and bug-fixes.
- · Aided acquisition process through participation in technical vetting including the discovery and mitigation of legal and licensing risks.

**GE Aviation Systems** Grand Rapids, MI

ROTATIONAL- PROGRAM MANAGEMENT & ENGINEERING

Aug. 2013 - Aug. 2016

- · Successfully led customer interactions with key programs resulting in \$6MM+ in sales and ungrounding of military aircraft fleets.
- · Assembled and led cross-functional team of 15 through manufacturing readiness review, transitioning a \$23MM program into production.
- · Verification of VHDL test procedures, creation of RTL code for adherence to emerging requirements, and automation of Libero build processes.
- · Recommended and implemented cost-saving configuration management procedures for a mature team.
- · Owned software integration of entire program, identified and resolved issues ranging from kernel to application code.
- · Independently authored cost-saving verification tooling that was fully adopted by the verification team.
- · Led and participated in formal reviews of certification and planning documents.

### Study Abroad, Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

LEAD DEVELOPER

Jul. 2012 - Aug. 2013 · Maintained and enhanced enterprise-grade polyglot applications encompassing all Study Abroad functions.

• Sole developer for second-largest Study Abroad program in the United States.

# **Proficient Technologies**

C/C++, Java, PHP, Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript (React, Angular, Ember, ECMAScript, TypeScript, jQuery,) HTML/CSS (SASS, Bootstrap,) VHDL, ASL, Bash, Zend Framework, Scala, ASP, Drupal, Relational Databases (Aurora, MySQL, PostgreSQL,) NoSQL (Mongo,) Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (Redshift, Aurora, ElastiCache, ElasticSearch, SQS, IAM, VPC, CloudWatch, EventBridge, EC2, S3, API Gateway,) ElasticSearch, Redis, DataDog, TeamCity, GitHub Actions, Spinnaker, Terraform, Chef, Atlassian Suite, Salesforce, Maven, Ant, Mathematica, MatLab, SPICE, Łack, VirtualBox, Git, Subversion, Photoshop, Illustrator, Libero, Dimensions, DOORS, PlantUML, macOS, Windows, Linux

### Education

#### **Michigan State University**

East Lansing, MI

Aug. 2013 - May. 2016

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING Focused primarily in NEMS/MEMS

### **Michigan State University**

East Lansing, MI

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Aug. 2009 - May. 2013

· Awarded Gerstacker Entrepreneurship Grant